# BRIAN T. OLSEN

3737 Peacock Ave. Apt 126 Miami, FL 33146 (561) 628-7871 | btolsen131@gmail.com

### **Career Profile**

Financial services professional with 4 years experience facilitating the operations of global equity portfolios in excess of \$40 billion assets under management. Established policies and procedures to outline responsibilities and roles of the operations department.

Core competencies include Python, SQL, R, Microsoft Excel, Microsoft PowerPoint, Financial Operations, Project Management, Data Analysis, and Bloomberg.

## **Experience**

INTECH INVESTMENT MANAGEMENT LLC (Global Quantitative Asset Manager)

Manager, Operations

Dec 2017 - Present

- Reports directly to Chief Operating Officer & General Counsel
- Trade Support functions including: Daily reconciliation of trade/broker files, instruct foreign exchange trades, coordinate opening of custodial bank accounts
- Operations functions including: Client Onboarding/ OffBoarding, facilitate cash and asset transfers
- Lead weekly meetings with various stakeholders in the operational set up of portfolios

FLORIDA HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES, Tallahassee FL

Legislative Intern

Jan 2016 - Mar 2016

- Created research reports on legislation for the Congressperson to use in debate
- Evaluated potential impact of amendments on short notice
- Met with lobbyist and interest group to discuss their goals and proposed legislation

## **Education**

Florida State University

Bachelors Graduated 2017

- Double Major: Economics, Political Science
- Cum Laude (GPA 3.5)
- Dean's List: Fall 2015-Spring 2017
- Relevant coursework: Financial Markets, Banking, and Monetary Policy, Decisions Under Risk & Uncertainty, Analysis of Economic Data, Introduction to Econometrics, Intermediate Economic Theory, Spreadsheets for Business, SAS Data & Statistical Analysis

### Misc.

CFA Investment Foundations Certificate Holder